Mobile: 07767 096709 E-mail: henryjheath@gmail.com Website: hiheath.github.io

# **HENRY HEATH**

#### **Motivation**

I want to solve difficult and worthwhile problems using technology.

I develop a Rails web API and JavaScript SDK to allow companies to

perform global identity verification using machine learning technology.

I worked as a software engineer in test, developing tools to automate

the testing of telecoms software. I wrote tools in Python and exposed

I won a company award for organising a group to share and

# **Experience**

#### Onfido

Software Engineer Jan 2016 - present London

#### **Metaswitch Networks**

Software Engineer Sept 2014 - Dec 2015 London

them to a team of testers through Django and Flask web apps.

### **Accomplishments**

**Accomplishments** 

develop Python knowledge.

- I won "Most Ambitious Hack" for a Hackathon project that applied machine learning algorithms to the internal bug and issues databases. This has since been turned into a tool that support engineers use to quickly resolve customers' issues.
- I mentored work experience students and interns.
- I organised monthly discussions between fellow engineers to improve the processes we use to test software.

# The Student White Tie Company

Co-founder, Web Developer 2013 - 2015 Oxford

At university I co-founded a business hiring out formal dress to students. We hired out our whole stock within a week of the website going live. We sold the business to current students who continue to operate it today.

## **Technical Skills**

# **Proficient**

Python, Django, Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, Docker

## Education

# New College, Oxford University

MPhys Physics, 2:1 2013 - 2014

#### New College, Oxford University

BA Hons Physics, 2:1 2010 - 2013

### Tiffin School

2003 - 2010

Kingston upon Thames

I specialised in the Physics of Oceans and Atmospheres. I completed a research project that simulated reduced precision hardware to improve the computational efficiency of weather and climate models.

I won the Gibbs prize for a talk I gave on "The Physics of Bicycles".

A-levels: A\*s in Maths, Further Maths, and Physics. A in Chemistry.

GCSFs: 10 A\*s.

#### Other Activities and Interests

Web Design I have designed and built several websites. The largest was for the

Harvard LGBTQ Conference 2016.

Startups I built a proof of concept website for a start up providing quotes for

funeral directors. I am currently building a marketplace to sell art from

up and coming artists.

Intermediate French I took a French module as part of my degree in 2012. I then completed

a two-week residential course in Montpellier in 2013 and a 10 week

course at City University London in 2014.

**RFU Qualified Rugby Referee** I am a qualified referee and a member of London Society of Rugby

Union Referees. I referee rugby matches most weekends and I am a

member of the London Referee Development Squad.

Editor of the college newspaper I managed a team of ten sub-editors to ensure that the fortnightly

student paper was published on time, as well as creating content

relevant and interesting to the readership.